Guide to the NYU Abu Dhabi Memory Project Collection AD.RG.023
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
- Office of Social Responsibility - Partner Interviews, OSR 10th Anniversary Project, 2021
  - Interview session with Yasir Ur Rehman and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (22:29), 9 June 2021; ADRG023_048 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_048)
    Audio-recorded Memory Project session with Yasir Ur Rehman, Control Room Operator in Public Safety Department, recorded on the 9th of June, 2021, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, a PPTP student for the Office of Social Responsibility and conducted as part of OSR's 10-year project and The Memory Project. The interview was recorded in-person on campus. It took place in the C2 building, outside the OSR's office.
    In this interview, Yasir Ur Rehman, Control Room Operator in Public Safety, shares his family background, life events, work life, and his journey to NYUAD. He starts by talking about his home in Islamabad, Pakistan, languages he speaks (Pothwari, Urdu, English, Arabic), and his education progression. He talks about his clerical job in the Ministry of Education (Islamabad). During that time, he was influenced by his cousin, so he applied for a G4S visa and moved to the UAE in 2005. He tells of his early struggles at his new workplace with long working hours and low salary, and poor accommodation. After a year, he returned to Pakistan for marriage and again came back to UAE in May 2008. One day, he heard about NYUAD, so he decided to apply and later got accepted. He marks it as one of the most successful events of his life. Yasir also explains about his day-to-day work at NYUAD- handling the public safety control room. Yasir happily shares about his family responsibility, love for his daughter, and expectations from his son. He repeatedly appreciates the caring and humble working environment and management of NYUAD.
  - Interview session with Jayaprakash Subramanian and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (11:35), 9 June 2021; ADRG023_049 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_049)
    Audio-recorded session with Jayaprakash Subramanian, Security Officer, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, PPTP student. Conducted as part of the Office of Social Responsibility (OSR) 10 Year Project/Memory Project Partnership. The location of the interview is C2 building, in front of the Office of Social Responsibility, NYUAD Saadiyat Campus.
    Jayaprakash describes his home in India, and how he comes from a farmer's family; he speaks Hindi and English. In 2008, he joined G4S, then two years later the company sent him on an interview at NYU Abu Dhabi, and he got the job in August, 2010. Before NYUAD, he had multiple jobs, working in New Delhi at a bakery, and an advertising agency. In his free time, he likes to cook, watch movies, and meet up with friends (although due to COVID he is limited in that regard). He has taken almost all OSR courses: Public Speaking, Intermediate English, Creative Writing, Excel Crash Course...He likes that he has become financially independent throughout his time at NYUAD, but he misses his family. He is looking forward to his daughter's graduation from high school and a continuation of a stable, secure life.
  - Interview session with Andrew Moriasi and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (21:10), 9 June 2021; ADRG023_050 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_050)
    Audio-recorded session with Andrew Moriasi, Security Officer, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, PPTP student. Conducted as part of the Office of Social Responsibility (OSR) 10 year Project/Memory Project Partnership. The location of the interview is C2 building, in front of the Office of Social Responsibility, NYUAD Saadiyat Campus.
    Andrew came to the UAE in 2007 and found work as a Security Officer, but then shortly after got the opportunity to do an interview with NYU Abu Dhabi and got the job as a Security Officer, where he received training, but he did additional studying on his own - he went on Coursera and got certified in First Aid and Mental First Aid, as a way to help his friends in crisis situations. He received certification in Religious Tolerance as well. Andrew reveals that he obtained a degree in Food Science in his home country -- Kenya -- and managed to teach his colleagues how to cook.
    He discusses how NYUAD allowed him to become financially stable and contribute to his children's college education and that he manages to call them every day to hear how they are doing. When asked, he tells Laura about the OSR courses. Then, Andrew shares that he had COVID in April, 2020, and how he felt during that time (fear of the unknown, solace in friendship) and that he managed to recover in about two weeks. Lastly, he shares what he likes most about working at NYUAD.
  - Interview session with Lilia Espanola Francisco and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (23:01), 10 June 2021; ADRG023_051 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_051)
    Audio-recorded session with Lilia Espanola Francisco, recorded on Thursday, June 10th, 2021 and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, PPTP student. Conducted as part of the Office of Social Responsibility NYUAD 10 Years book project, in partnership with The Memory Project.
    Lilia Francisco has been working at NYUAD as a Security guard with the Public Safety team for ten years. She is from San Mariano, the Philippines. After their family business went bankrupt, Lilia decided to work abroad, leaving behind her husband and four children. Initially, she was supposed to work in Afghanistan, however upon her arrival to the UAE in order to cross the border, she learned about a vacancy at NYUAD. Without prior experience of working in Public Safety, she completed the necessary training and participated in adult education courses - mainly in English language and IELTS preparatory courses. While it is difficult to be far away from her family, Lilia is working tirelessly to ensure a good quality of life for her children.
  - Interview session with Thomas Mathew Kulathingal and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (23:47), 10 June 2021; ADRG023_052 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_052)
    Audio-recorded session with Thomas Mathew Kulathingal, Public Safety Officer, recorded on Thursday, June 10th, 2021 and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, from the Office of Social Responsibility. Conducted as part of The Memory Project and as part of the Office of Social Responsibility's 10th Anniversary Book Project.
    Thomas Mathew Kulathingal has started his 12th year at NYUAD as a Public Safety Officer. He is originally from Kerala, in the southern part of India, but he has been in Abu Dhabi since 2006. Thomas Mathew Kulathingal speaks Malayalam, Hindi, Tamil, and a little bit of Kanera language, as well as English. Back in Kerala, he completed a pre-degree program and continued his studies in a technical institute, and worked in agricultural business. After working in Kerala, he came to Abu Dhabi in November, 2006. He saw the NYUAD building in downtown Abu Dhabi while it was still in construction, and later sent his CV and got invited for an interview. During his time at NYUAD, Thomas Kulathingal took classes on Financial literacy, PowerPoint, Excel, Theatre, Photography, and Public speaking. While the pandemic has impacted the way the staff spend their leisure time and visit their families back home, Thomas Mathew Kulathingal also uses his free time to talk to his family and try out new recipes.
  - Interview session with Kavitha Karunakarakurup and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (13:06), 15 June 2021; ADRG023_053 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_053)
    Audio interview session with Kavitha Karunakarakurup, Public Safety (G4S) officer, recorded on Tuesday, 15th June, 2021, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, a PPTP student for the Office of Social Responsibility(OSR). Conducted as part of the OSR's 10 Years at NYUAD Book Project, in partnership with The Memory Project. The interview was recorded in-person on campus. It took place in the C2 building, outside the OSR's office.
    in Kerala, India, languages she speaks (Malayalam, Hindi,and English), and her education progression (B.A. in history). Kavita reflects on her work as a stenographer back in New Delhi for 8 years. Next, she speaks about her initial struggle at different workplaces (MENA Building, Emirates Palace) after moving to the UAE. She shares how glad she was to get a job offer at NYUAD. She also describes her role working as Public Safety Officer on the highline. She talks about the significance of the English language course that she took (offered by the OSR). She mentions that she's been financially independent and has built a house while looking after the family. Finally, she reveals her interest in gardening and how she grows vegetables and plants.
  - Interview session with Sonu Thomas and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (11:01), 16 June 2021; ADRG023_054 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_054)
    Audio-recorded session with Sonu Thomas, Light Driver for Global Wings, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, PPTP student. Conducted as part of the Office of Social Responsibility (OSR) 10 year Project/Memory Project Partnership. The location of the interview is The Welcome Center of NYUAD, Saadiyat Campus. There are two people present at the interview site - the interviewer and interviewee. There is a short, loud thud at 02:40. At 09:05, Sonu looks for a picture of the house he built in India to show Laura. At 09:51-10:06, Sonu looks up his wife's Youtube channel and Facebook page, and at 10:07 he plays the song for Laura. At 10:35, there is another short, loud thud.
    Sonu Thomas is from Kerala, India, and before NYUAD he was working in Delhi in an electronics company. He came to Dubai, UAE in 2003, after his friends told him about the possibilities there, and then in 2005 he took a vacation to get married in India. But he returned with his wife immediately to Dubai, and in 2007 he moved to Abu Dhabi, where his wife got the job of a professional Malayalee singer (her main occupation is a nurse at Corniche Hospital). His two daughters are studying in Abu Dhabi. Throughout working for Abu Dhabi, he changed employment in three different companies related to driving. He got accepted to work for NYUAD at the very beginning, when there were only two drivers. He has taken two OSR courses: English and Arabic. He is satisfied with his NYUAD job, and it has allowed him and his family to lead a comfortable life. He built a home for his parents back in India.
  - Interview session with Abdul Jaleel and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (05:52), 16 June 2021; ADRG023_055 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_055)
    Audio-recorded session with Abdul Jaleel, Bus Driver, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, PPTP student. Conducted as part of the Office of Social Responsibility (OSR) 10 year Project/Memory Project Partnership.
    In this interview session, Abdul talks about his origin - he is from the village of Kerala, India, and he came directly from there to Abu Dhabi. He speaks Malayalam. Before working at NYUAD, he was working at a maintenance company in Abu Dhabi. He transferred from Global Wings to NYUAD. His kids are back in Kerala, studying, and he sees them whenever he visits. At NYUAD, he drives the shuttle from campus to Yas Mall and Al Wadha. He took some OSR classes at DTC, when NYUAD was at the Downtown Campus. With the salary from NYUAD, he was able to build a home back in Kerala and help his children pursue a better education.
  - Interview session with Tara Gurung and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (15:48), 21 June 2021; ADRG023_056 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_056)
    Audio-recorded session with Tara Gurung, Public Safety Officer, recorded on Monday, June 21st, 2021, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, Office of Social Responsibility PPTP Student. Conducted as part of The Memory Project and the 10th Anniversary Book Project. The interview takes place outside the Office of Social Responsibility office, on the Ground floor of NYUAD campus on Saadiyat Island.
    Tara Gurung is a Public Safety Officer that specializes in Access Control and Customer Service. She is originally from Itahari area, Nepal, 8 hours away from the capital city of Kathmandu. In addition to English, Tara speaks Nepali, Hindi, and a bit of Arabic. Prior to joining NYUAD, she worked as a primary school teacher back in Nepal. Tara joined G4S and arrived in the UAE on April 16, 2008, and she joined NYUAD as a Public Safety Officer on March 6, 2010. During her time here, Tara participated in workshops provided by the Office of Social Responsibility on computer literacy and cooking. In this session, Tara also shares her memories about Sama Tower. She dedicates her free time to keeping in touch with her family, and hopes to go back to Nepal in the future and be with them.
  - Interview session with Mohammed Hoque and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (37:37), 21 June 2021; ADRG023_057 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_057)
    Audio-recorded session with Mohammed Hoque, Worker at ADNH, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, PPTP student. Conducted as part of the Office of Social Responsibility (OSR) 10 year Project/Memory Project Partnership. The interview takes place outside of the Office of Social Responsibility, Ground floor of C2, NYUAD, Saadiyat Campus. There are two people present at the interview site - the interviewer and interviewee. At 14:37, 16:45, 17:06, 17:43, 24:15, several people are talking in the background. At 17:49, there is a quick, sharp sound, perhaps from a microphone. At 31:32, 31:43, some people are passing by with a cleaning cart.
    Mohammed Haque is from Lakshmipur District, near Meghna River, Bangladesh. He was working in Saudi Arabia, for Saudi Arabian Airlines, then he joined NYU Abu Dhabi in 2011, and throughout his time at NYUAD, he has worked in multiple positions under ADNH - dining hall and coffee shops at Sama Tower, and even as a Store Clerk in 2014. He has taken English courses at OSR and has attended multiple workshops. He speaks Bengali, English, and Arabic. He worked at the Airlines until 2007, and for a short period of time he went back home to Bangladesh and immediately returned to Abu Dhabi, finding a job at the Abu Dhabi Court. Throughout the interview, he explains Bangladeshi culture and the feeling of responsibility of being the breadwinner. He also states that he talks to his family two to three times a day and that he is able to financially support his wife who is sick, thanking NYUAD for that possibility. He then goes on to describe his job position in Saudi Arabia, opportunities for investment with his friend, and taking care of his family, especially his wife who had to undergo surgery. In the future, he plans to open up a water-based business and he is looking forward to the day when his children study at NYUAD.
  - Interview session with Earnie Agramonte Odieres and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (17:30), 21 June 2021; ADRG023_058 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_058)
    Interview session with Earnie Agramonte Odieres, Assistant Chef at NYUAD Dining Department, recorded on Monday, 21st June, 2021, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, a PPTP student for the Office of Social Responsibility(OSR). Conducted as part of the OSR's 10 Years at NYUAD Book Project, in partnership with The Memory Project. The interview took place at the Torch Club (top of D2).
    In this interview, Earnie shares about his family, life events, work life, and his journey to NYUAD. He describes his role working as Assistant Chef, planning and preparing the cold and hot kitchen. He shares about his home in Visayas, Philippines, languages he speaks (English, Tagalog, Hiligayhon), and his education progression (Bachelor of Science in Education). Earnie reflects on his work as a high school teacher back in the Philippines for six months before moving to the UAE. Next, he mentions that he was very lucky to have his first job (started as waiter) at NYUAD. Earnie also reveals the difference he has seen from Sama Tower DTC to the larger Saadiyat Campus. He mentions that he's been financially independent and has built a house, bought land, and started a small renting business. Finally, he appreciates the English course he has taken, which was offered by the OSR, and says he loves everyone at NYUAD.
  - Interview session with Nadir Khan and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (22:10), 22 June 2021; ADRG023_059 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_059)
    Interview session with Nadir Khan, Shift Supervisor in Public Safety, recorded on Tuesday, 22nd June, 2021, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, a PPTP student for the Office of Social Responsibility(OSR). Conducted as part of the OSR's 10 Years at NYUAD Book Project, in partnership with The Memory Project. The interview was recorded over Zoom.
    In this interview, Nadir shares about his family, life events, work life, and his journey to NYUAD. He describes his role working as Shift Supervisor, deploying and looking after the requirements of his colleagues. He speaks about his home in Kashmir, Pakistan, languages he speaks (Urdu, English), and his education progression (Intermediate in Commerce). Nadir reflects on his work in the Pakistani Armed Forces for six years and his resignation. Next, he mentions his first work in the UAE in the Armed Forces Officer Club at Abu Dhabi. He shares how glad he was to get a job offer at NYUAD. Nadir also reveals the difference he has seen from Sama Tower DTC to the larger Saadiyat Campus. He talks about the significance of different language and computer courses that he has taken (offered by the OSR). He mentions that he's been financially independent and has built a house while looking after the family. Finally, he proudly says that he loves every moment spent at NYUAD and hopes to return to his home country in near future.
  - Interview session with Lailani Vidal and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (32:19), 22 June 2021; ADRG023_060 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_060)
    Audio-recorded session with Lailani Vidal, Senior Administrator at Serco, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, PPTP student. Conducted as part of the Office of Social Responsibility (OSR) 10 year Project/Memory Project Partnership. The interview takes place outside of the Office of Social Responsibility, on the ground floor of C2, at NYU Abu Dhabi, Saadiyat Island. There are two people present at the interview site - the interviewer and the interviewee. At 24:52-25:58, loud yelling and talking noises from children are noticeable.
    Lailani started working for NYUAD in 2010, at the Downtown Campus as an Administrative Assistant for Facility Management under Serco. She explains the difference between soft and hard services in the industry, and she explains her and her colleagues' responsibilities in this job, emphasizing teamwork as crucial for the success of their jobs. She is from the Philippines and she speaks Tagalog, English, and a little bit of Japanese because she worked for a Japanese company back home. She opens up about her struggles obtaining a Bachelor's degree in Industrial Engineering, and how she managed to work in the morning, and study in the afternoon. Then, she reflects on financial struggles and climbing ladders at NYUAD, as well as starting out in the UAE and slowly bringing her family there. She developed a plan for taking care of her kids in agreement with her husband in light of Covid-19, thanks to the flexibility of working from home by Serco. Her intentions for the future include creating a business in the Philippines, probably in the IT sector. She reflects on her time in DTC, and she states that she's taken the English, Arabic, and Excel OSR courses while encouraging other Filipino staff to participate in the programs. She explains that one of her boys will participate in the Boys Education Network, for which Lailani is really excited, and that the other loves spending time at NYUAD. She ends by sharing words of encouragement she tells her oldest son.
  - Interview session with Richelle Vallejos and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (10:09), 23 June 2021; ADRG023_061 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_061)
    Audio-recorded session with Richelle Vallejos, Security Officer, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, PPTP student. Conducted as part of the Office of Social Responsibility (OSR) 10 year Project/Memory Project Partnership.
    In this interview session, Richelle talks about herself, her family, previous employment, working at NYUAD, and hopes for the future. She is from the Philippines and she is a Security Officer in A1B. She speaks English and Tagalog. She has an undergraduate degree in Computer Security. Her father used to work in the UAE, and he brought her here. With the help of her aunt, who was working in G4S, she managed to get a job there. She came to the UAE, hoping to help out her family, because back home Richelle and her family did not have land or a house, so they stayed with her aunt for about two years. Her father—who worked in a construction company—financially helped them build a house. Then, two out of her three brothers moved to the UAE. She was able to take an English course which is offered by the Office of Social Responsibility. Her plans for the future include moving home to spend some time with her family and potentially finding love and building a family.
  - Interview session with Madel De la Cruz and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (15:30), 23 June 2021; ADRG023_062 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_062)
    Audio-recorded session with Madel De la Cruz, CCTV Supervisor, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, PPTP student. Conducted as part of the Office of Social Responsibility (OSR) 10 year Project/Memory Project Partnership. The interview takes place outside of the Office of Social Responsibility, on the ground floor of C2, at NYU Abu Dhabi, Saadiyat Island. There are two people present at the interview site - the interviewer and the interviewee. At 11:45, there is light talking in the background, which slowly by 14:00 starts getting louder.
    In this interview session, Madel shares stories of her life before and during working at NYU Abu Dhabi. She starts by saying that she was born and lived close to Manila, Philippines. She speaks Tagalog and English. While in the Philippines, she graduated with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering, and she worked there for about six years, in accounting for a newspaper company rather than her field. Then, a friend told her about a great opportunity for work at G4S in the UAE. Madel was interested in the idea and decided to apply to work for G4S in NYUAD. Throughout the years, she managed to transform her role from a Control Room Operator to a Control Room Supervisor, spanning her career at NYUAD to 11 years and counting. What she especially likes about the working environment there is that even security guards are taken care of, and made to feel comfortable. Madel was a part of the DTC Campus as well, in Sama Tower, and she draws a comparison between the two campuses, saying that Saadiyat is bigger and it's harder to get to know everyone. Then, she reflects on her relationship with her daughter and opens up about a difficult life event with her mother. Madel has taken English and Financial Literacy courses, and Computer classes. She shares some memorable events at NYUAD like Iftar and Staff Appreciation Week and hopes to perhaps move to Canada with her daughter in the future.
  - Interview session with Bakht Munir Khan and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (10:08), 10 June 2021; ADRG023_066 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_066)
    Audio-recorded session with Bakht Munir Khan, Security Officer at Public Safety, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, PPTP student. Conducted as part of the Office of Social Responsibility (OSR) 10 year Project/Memory Project Partnership.